Finding Aid to Framed Items from the Collections of The Bancroft Library
The Bancroft Library
- Individual Framed Items
  - [Adobe, Rancho Santa Margarita(?)], [ca. 1885]; Walker, James; BANC PIC 1971.005--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 25 x 44.8 cm. Exhibition and provenance information on verso.
    View of ranchers roping a cow in front of an adobe house. Possibly Rancho Santa Margarita, (San Luis Obispo County?) Calif.
  - [Corral, Rancho Santa Margarita(?)], [ca. 1885]; Walker, James; BANC PIC 1971.006--FR; 1 painting: oil on canvas; visible image 25.2 x 45.2 cm. Numerous (on verso).
    Thatched stick corral on open plain with mountains in distance. Possibly Rancho Santa Margarita, (San Luis Obispo County?) Calif.
    Oil paintings; Corrals -- California -- Pictorial works; Ranchers -- California -- Pictorial works; Rancho Santa Margarita (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - [Padron], [ca. 1885]; Walker, James; BANC PIC 1971.007--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 29.2 x 24.5 cm. Painted signature (LL): J. Walker. Handwritten title (verso).
    Man in fancy dress on horseback, presumably a Spanish Califorian rancher.
    Oil paintings; Ranchers -- California -- Pictorial works
  - [Vaquero], [ca. 1885]; Walker, James; BANC PIC 1971.008--FR; 1 painting: oil on canvas; vi 29.2 x 24.5 cm. Painted signature (LL): J. Walker. Handwritten title (verso).
    Young man on horseback, presumably on a Californian rancho.
    Oil paintings; Cowboys -- California -- Pictorial works
  - California fruit: paintur for C.A. Shelton., [ca. 1855]; Nahl, Charles Christian; BANC PIC 1971.009--FR; 1 painting on paper: watercolor; visible image 22.7 x 35 cm. Handlettered title and signature (LC): California Fruit paintur for C. A. Shelton / by Charles Nahl.
    Bowl including apples, pears, grapes and other fruits.
    Watercolors; Still lifes; Fruit -- California -- Pictorial works
  - [San Francisco beach, Seal Rock, and Cliff House], [188-?]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1971.010--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 34.8 x 60.2 cm.
    View from Ocean Beach looking north toward the Cliff House and Seal Rocks; bathers and a dog on the beach, and a steamship in the distance.
    Oil paintings; San Francisco (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Seal Rocks (San Francisco, Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Cliff House (San Francisco, Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Leisure -- California -- San Francisco -- Pictorial works; Beaches -- California -- San Francisco -- Pictorial works; Ocean Beach (San Francisco, Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - The Grizzly, [ca. 1890]; Hill, Thomas; BANC PIC 1971.011--FR; 1 painting on wood panel: oil; 106.6 x 17.7 cm. Signature (LR): T. Hill. Title (LC): The / Grizzly.
    Giant Sequoia with two figures on horseback in foreground.
    Gift of Warren Howell, 1971. ​A sale catalog of Fifth Avenue Art Galleries​ (New York) for Feb. 11-13, 1903, lists a pair of Hill paintings on "two panels from giant trees of California", "The Grizzly and the Neowna [sic]," which were from "the Fields' collection." Several other lots are noted as from the collection of Justice Stephen Field, including another by Hill. (See: Catalogue of high-class oil paintings by American and European artists. Lot 84. https://archive.org/details/b1491310; visited December 2017.) There is no firm evidence linking the Bancroft Library panels to the items in this sale.
    Oil paintings; Yosemite National Park (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Giant sequoia -- California -- Pictorial works; Grizzly Giant (Tree) -- Pictorial works; Mariposa Grove (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - The Wawona, [ca. 1890]; Hill, Thomas; BANC PIC 1971.012--FR; 1 painting on wood panel: oil; 106.7 x 17.8 cm. Signature (LR): T. Hill. Painted title (LC): The / Wawona.
    Giant Sequoia showing tunnel through trunk.
    Oil paintings; Yosemite National Park (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Giant sequoia -- California -- Pictorial works; Mariposa Grove (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Wawona (Tree) -- Pictorial works
  - Confluence of the Jefferson, Madison, and Gallatin Rivers to Form the Missouri River in S.W. Montana, 1917, Paxson, E.S.; BANC PIC 1971.013--FR; 1 painting on paper: watercolor; 24.7 x 34.7 cm. Painted signature and date (LR): E.S. Paxson / -1917-. Title from label on verso. Acquisition information on label on verso. UC inventory label (verso): 71-10-00470.
    Landscape view from the river bank in the Three Forks region of Montana.
    Watercolors; Rivers -- Montana -- Pictorial works; Three Forks Region (Mont.) -- Pictorial works; Landscapes (Representations) -- Montana
  - A prune orchard, Saratoga, California, [1927]; Wores, Theodore; BANC PIC 1971.016--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 29.4 x 44.2 cm. Signature (LR): Theodore Wores.
    Landscape with plum trees in bloom and poppies.
    Oil paintings; Landscapes (Representations) -- California -- Saratoga; Saratoga (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Orchards -- California -- Saratoga -- Pictorial works
  - [Portrait of Herbert E. Bolton]: [Director of The Bancroft Library, 1916-1942], [1970]; Lazcano, J.; BANC PIC 1971.019--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 79.8 x 75 cm. Painted signature (LR): J. Lazcano.
    Half length seated portrait of former director reading a book
    Oil paintings; Portraits; Bancroft Library. -- Director -- Portraits; Bolton, Herbert Eugene, -- 1870-1953 -- Portratis
  - [A Modoc brave on the warpath], [ca. 1873]; Muybridge, Eadweard; Bradley & Rulofson; BANC PIC 1971.055:1627--FR; 1 photograph: stereograph; on mount 8.5 x 17.7 cm. Printed (on mount): The Modoc War / illustrated by Muybridge / Published by Bradley & Rulofson. Exhibition information on verso.
    Modoc Indians -- Wars, 1873 -- Photographs; Stereographs
  - [Mountain lion], [ca. 1945]; Proctor, A. Phimister (Alexander Phimister); BANC PIC 19xx.503--PIC; 1 print: etching; visible image 16 x 17.6 cm. Etched initials (LR in image): A.P.P. Handwritten signature (LR): A Phimister Proctor; (LC): To my good friend / Francis Farquhor- / from A. Phimister Proctor - Nov. 29 - [1]945.
    Snarling mountain lion perched on a hill.
  - [Landscape in the Sierra Nevada mountains], [ca. 1940]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1972.003--FR; 1 painting on canvas mounted on cardboard: oil; 20.5 x 27.8 cm.
    View of meadow with mountains in distance.
    Oil paintings; Landscapes (Representations) -- Sierra Nevada (Calif. and Nev.); Sierra Nevada (Calif. and Nev.) -- Pictorial works
  - [The camp ground], [191-?]; Ring, B. (Alice B.?); BANC PIC 1972.005--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 59.5 x 89 cm. Signature (LL): BRing.
    A California resort camp with large tents, oak trees, and figures. Large communal tent at left. Outdoor cooking area set up in left foreground. Several groups of men, women, and children reading, playing cards, relaxing and preparing to hunt.
    Oil paintings; Leisure -- California -- Pictorial works; Camping -- California -- Pictorial works
  - [Pioche, Lincoln County, Nevada], August 1870; Schofield, George; BANC PIC 1972.006--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 43.5 69.5 cm. Painted signature and date (LL): G. Schofield / Aug. 1870. Label (verso of frame): Pioche / 19 miles from Bodie, California [...]
    View of town looking northwesterly from the north slope of Treasure Hill. Hill at center is a quartzite knoll. Mine building at center is thought to be the Meadow Valley no.3 shaft.
    Oil paintings; Mines and mineral resources -- Nevada -- Pioche -- Pictorial works; Mining districts -- Nevada -- Pictorial works; Pioche (Nev.) -- Pictorial works
  - [Portrait of Henry Durant]: [first president of the University of California], [ca. 1845]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1972.027--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 68.4 x 55.5 cm.
    Bust length portrait.
    Oil paintings; Portraits; University of California (1868-1952). -- President -- Portraits; Durant, Henry, -- 1802-1875 -- Portraits
  - [Portrait of Inez Ghirardelli], [ca. 1940]; Lehman, Carlton; BANC PIC 1973.014--FR; 1 painting on heavy panel: tempera; visible image 48 x 63 cm. Label (verso, UL) from Golden Gate International Exposition May 25th - September 29th, 1940. Names artist as Carleton Lehman, registration # 2549.
    Half length seated portrait. Unfinished scene (described separately) on verso.
    Portraits; Tempera paintings; Ghirardelli, Ynez, -- 1909- -- Portraits
  - Lakeport, Lake County, California: The Switzerland of America., c1888; Inchbold, Stanley; BANC PIC 1973.015--D; 1 print: artotype; sheet 53 x 71 cm. Printed title (LC). Printed signature (LR in image): Drawn by Stanley Inchbold Upper Lake, Lake Co. Cal. Printed (LR out side of image): Britton & Rey, Arto: San Francisco; (LL): Entered according to act of Congress in the year 1888 by Stanley Inchbold, Upper Lake, in the office of the Librarian of Congress at Washington; (LC below title): Stanley Inchbold, Upper Lake, Lake Co. Cal., late prof. of drawing at the University Coll. Sch: London, Eng.: certificated art master from South Kensington Govt. School, London, Eng. Library of Congress copyright stamp (LL).
    Content/DescriptionLarge central image is overview of the town, waterfront and distant hills, showing docks, buildings and farms. Marginal images of prominent businesses and landmarks include map of Plates Addition, tin shop and hardware storefront on Chamblin block, Witter Springs [resort] near Upper Lake, H. Cohn & Son grocery and hardware store, Farmers Savings Bank storefront, McCraney & Sons storefront, Mound Cottages Hotel, Bank of Lake storefront, Lakeport Democrat storefront, Whitton's Stable, Uncle Sam Mountain from Upper Lake, Tunis Lumber Merchant, storefronts on Levy block 1875, Pioneer Store.
    Bird's-eye views; Lakeport (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Lakeport (Calif.) -- Aerial views; Collotypes
  - [Still life]: [the Daily Independent], [ca. 1889]; S.M. (of San Diego); BANC PIC 1973.019--FR; 1 painting: oil; 33.2 x 45.7 cm. Painted (LR): S. M. San Diego. Label detailing provenance on verso.
    The Daily Independent was founded in 1883 by George P. Tebbetts. The painting was presented by Tebbetts' son, Nathan A. Tebbetts, to Thomas More Storke in commemoration of the friendship between their fathers George Tebbetts and Judge Charles A. Storke. Judge Storke purchased the paper and changed the name to the Santa Barbara News Press. T.M. Storke was editor.
    Folded newspaper, Daily Independent, (Vol. XVIII--No. 60. Santa Barbara Wednesday evening) laying on table next to tooled leather cigar pouch; lit cigar rests on table.
    Oil paintings; Still lifes
  - [Looking down Yosemite Valley], [ca. 1870]; Bierstadt, Albert; Dillmann, J.J.; Deldruck v. Breidenbach & Co. (Dusseldorf, Germany); BANC PIC 1974.009--FR; 1 print: chromolithograph; visible image 53.5 x 81.7 cm. Printed signature (LR): A. Bierstadt. Printed (LL): J.J. Dillmann Lith; (LC): Deldruck v. Breidenbach & Co. in Dusseldorf.
    View looking towards Royal Arches; Half Dome at right, Yosemite Falls at left, Merced River below, and Mount Watkins in distance.
    Yosemite Valley (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Chromolithographs
  - [Sutro Baths], [ca. 1900]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1974.014-ROLL; 1 print (composite of multiple sheets) mounted on canvas: chromolithograph; printed area 197.5 x 203.5 cm.
    Interior view of baths showing large pool, smaller pools, and platforms. Onlookers on upper platforms viewing mostly male bathers. Structure of building detailed.
    San Francisco (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Leisure -- California -- San Francisco -- Pictorial works; Chromolithographs; Sutro Baths -- Pictorial works; Public baths -- California -- San Francisco -- Pictorial works
  - [View of Avalon Harbor, Santa Catalina Island, Calif.], c1905; Kurtz and Allison; BANC PIC 1975.009--FR; 1 print: chromolithograph; visible image 51.2 x 65.6 cm. Printed title (LC): Avalon, Santa Catalina Island Cal.
    View overlooking bay and harbor showing boating activity, docks, and buildings along shore.
    Chromolithographs; Landscapes (Representations) -- California -- Santa Catalina Island; Santa Catalina Island (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - [Avalon Bay, Santa Catalina Island], [ca. 1900]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1975.031--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 54.9 x 81.9 cm.
    View of harbor with a small number of buildings on the shore. Small sailing vessels and a ferry on the water.
    Oil paintings; Landscapes (Representations) -- California -- Santa Catalina Island; Santa Catalina Island (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - [California landscape with poppies], [ca. 1925]; Redmond, Granville; BANC PIC 1976.006--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 75.3 x 100.5 cm. Signature (LL): Grandville Redmond.
    Rolling green foothills with oak trees and poppies in the foreground; mountains in the distance.
    Oil paintings; Landscapes (Representations) -- California; Poppies -- Pictorial works
  - [Laguna Beach, Calif.], [ca. 1918]; Redmond, Granville; BANC PIC 1976.008--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 29.7 x 40 cm. Painted signature (LR): Granville Redmond.
    View of coastline with several figures on the beach under umbrellas and in the water.
    Oil paintings; Landscapes; Laguna Beach (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - [Yosemite Valley by moonlight, Calif.], [ca. 1890]; Sears, Benjamin Willard; BANC PIC 1976.019--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 45.7 x 32.3 cm. Painted signature (LR): Ben. W. Sears.
    Nocturnal view of El Capitan with small campfire visible on the valley floor.
    Oil paintings; Yosemite Valley (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - [Indian war party], [ca. 1930]; Borein, Edward; BANC PIC 1976.042--FR; 1 print: etching; visible image 14.3 x 19.4 cm. Handwritten signature (LR): Edward Borein. Insignia? (LL).
    Four native American Indians on horseback; three wear full feather headresses and each carries either a spear or staff.
    Indians of North America -- West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Etchings
  - Home-Front Hero, Jan. 15, 1943; Goldberg, Rube; BANC PIC 1976.045--FR; 1 drawing: crayon, ink, and gouache; visible image 34 x 27.7 cm. Handwritten signature (LR): Rube Goldberg. Handwritten inscription (LL): With / all good wishes / to commissioner / Albert Pleydell / [signed] Rube Goldberg / Jan. 15, 1943.
    Satirical cartoon of horse in relation to gas rationing and beef shortage during the World War II.
    Cartoons (Commentary); Drawings
  - [Self portrait of Gottardo Piazzoni sketching in landscape], 1903; Piazzoni, Gottardo; BANC PIC 1977.013--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 16.8 x 12 cm. Painted signature and date (LR): G. Piazzoni 03.
    Oil paintings; Landscapes; Self-Portraits
  - Chaucer's Canterbury pilgrims, [not before 1810]; Blake, William; BANC PIC 1977.017--FR; 1 print: steel engraving (second state); visible image 35 x 96.5 cm. Printed title (LC). (Printed below title): Painted in fresco by William Blake & by him engraved & published October 8, 1810, at no. 28 corner of Broad Street Golden Square. engraving
    Large group on horseback in procession from gothic style gate at left. Characters named in margin below image.
    Canterbury (England); Chaucer, Geoffrey, -- d. 1400. -- Canterbury tales -- Pictorial works; Intaglio prints; Pilgrims and pilgrimages -- England -- Canterbury -- Pictorial works
  - [Landscape with eucalyptus trees, Santa Barbara foothills, Calif.], [ca. 1915]; Otte, William Louis; BANC PIC 1977.040--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 54.2 x 69.7 cm. Signature (LR): William Louis Otte (additional signature visible above present).
    Eucalyptus trees in foreground with mountains in distance.
    Oil paintings; Landscapes (Representations) -- California
  - [Cowboy chasing a steer], [ca. 1920]; Borein, Edward; BANC PIC 1977.052--FR; 1 painting: watercolor on paper; visible image 11.7 x 18.9 cm. Handwritten signature (LR): Edward Borein.
    Watercolors; West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Cowboys -- California -- Pictorial works; Beef cattle -- West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works
  - [Two cowboys roping a steer], [ca. 1920]; Borein, Edward; BANC PIC 1977.053--FR; 1 painting: watercolor on paper; visible image 15.8 x 20.7 cm. Handwritten signature (LR): Edward Borein.
    Watercolors; West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Beef cattle -- West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Cowboys -- West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works
  - [Nudes embracing / photographed by Tom Weir], c1965; Weir, Thomas; BANC PIC 1977.116--FR; 1 photograph mounted on masonite; 28.5 x 50 cm. Handwritten photographer's label (verso): To Lawrence Ferlinghetti / 2nd Dec. 1965 / [signed] Thomas Weir.
    Image reproduced in City Lights Journal # 3 (1965).
    Nudes
  - [Old Mission Sonoma, Calif.], [ca. 1905]; Macartney, Harry; BANC PIC 1978.101--FR; 1 painting on academy board: oil; visible image 24 x 31 cm. Painted signature (LR): H. Macartney. Stamp (verso): Regal / Canvas Boards / size 10 x 13. Handwritten (verso): Old Mission / Sonoma / H Macartney / 1791 Pine St. / City. Additional auction information partially visible on verso.
    View of Mission in evening.
    Oil paintings; Mission San Francisco Solano (Sonoma, Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Missions
  - Carmel, 1938; Heyneman, Julie Helen; BANC PIC 1978.123--FR; 1 painting on academy board: oil; visible image 35 x 45.5 cm. Handwritten signature, title, and date (LR): Julie Heyneman. / Carmel 1938.
    View of beach at Carmel looking north with Pebble Beach and northern point in distance.
    Oil paintings; Carmel (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - [Emilio Segre], [19--]; Chamberlain, June; BANC PIC 1978.187--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 80 x 59.5 cm. Painted signature (LC): June S. Chamberlain ©. Sitter's name appears on papers on desk.
    Half length portrait of the scientist seated at a desk in his office. Papers relating to light spectrum and related sciences scattered on desk.
    Segrè, Emilio -- Portraits; Scientists -- Portraits
  - [Mission San Juan Capistrano], 1886; Cole, Joseph Foxcroft; BANC PIC 1979.007--FR; 1 painting on paper: watercolor; visible image 36.9 x 50.9 cm. Painted signature and date (LR): J. Foxcroft Cole, 1886.
    Distant view across open pasture toward mission buildings.
    Spanish mission buildings -- California -- Pictorial works; Watercolors; California -- Pictorial works
  - [Chinatown Alley, Sing Yuen Washing & Ironing], [1885]; Hahn, Karl Wilhelm; BANC PIC 1979.008--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 45 x 33.5 cm. Painted signature (LR): Wm Hahn.
    Dark alley surrounded by buildings; several figures involved in various activities; ducks and chickens in scene.
    Oil paintings; Chinese -- California -- Pictorial works
  - Chapel of the Mission of San Luis Rey. S. California, 1876; Wiles, Lemuel; BANC PIC 1979.009--FR; 1 painting on board: oil; visible image 16.8 x 14.2 cm. Painted signature and date (LR): L M. Wiles / 1876. Painted title (plaque on frame). Handwritten (panel verso): Chapel of the Mission of San Luis Rey. S. California / L.M. Wiles / N.Y. 1876. Handwritten (LR): Moonlight- / Chapel at / San Luis Rey.
    Ruined chapel with belltower behind and church buildings to right. Cemetery crosses in foreground.
    Oil paintings; Spanish mission buildings -- California -- Pictorial works; San Luis Rey Mission (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - Mission of San Carlos, Near Monterey, California, 1876; Wiles. Lemuel Maynard; BANC PIC 1979.010--FR; 1 painting on board: oil; visible image 20 x 30.5 cm. Painted signature and date (LR): L.M. Wiles 1876. Painted title (plaque on frame). Handwritten (panel verso): Mission of San Carlos near Monterey California / N.Y. 1876 / L.M. Wiles.
    View of eastern façade of Church.
    Oil paintings; Spanish mission buildings -- California -- Pictorial works; California -- Pictorial works
  - Mission of San Juan Capistrano. S. California, 1876; Wiles, Lemuel Maynard; BANC PIC 1979.011--FR; 1 painting on board: oil; visible image 19.9 x 30.2 cm. Painted signature and date (LR): L M Wiles / 1876. Painted title (plaque on frame). Handwritten (panel verso): Mission of San Juan Capistrano. S. California / L.M. Wiles- / N.Y. 1876-.
    Ruins of chapel with bells at left and figures and mountains at right.
    Oil paintings; Spanish mission buildings -- California -- Pictorial works; San Juan Capistrano (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - Mount San Bernardino from the Mission Ruins, S. California, 1876; Wiles, Lemuel Maynard; BANC PIC 1979.012--FR; 1 painting on [slate?] panel: oil; visible image 24.5 x 48.9 cm. Painted signature and date (LL): L.M. Wiles / 1876. Painted title (plaque on frame). Handwritten (panel verso): Mount San Bernardino from the Mission Ruins, S. California / L. M. Wiles / N.Y. 1876.
    View overlooking valley from atop stone wall; mission ruins at right, small house at left, and snow-covered mountains in distance.
    Oil paintings; Landscapes (Representations) -- California; Spanish mission buildings -- California -- Pictorial works; Mountains -- Pictorial works
  - On the Chagres River, C[entral] America, 1876; Wiles Lemuel; BANC PIC 1979.013--FR; 1 painting on panel: oil; visible image 19 x 15.8 cm. Painted signature and date (LL): L.M. Wiles / 1876. Painted title (plaque on frame). Handwritten (panel verso): On the Chagres, C. America / L.M. Wiles / (LL) N.Y. 1876.
    View looking down river with the sun low above the distant mountains. Lush tropical vegetation along the shore, a small boat on the water, and huts visible in the distance.
  - View in Panama, C[entral] America, 1876; Wiles Lemuel; BANC PIC 1979.014--FR; 1 painting on panel: oil; visible image 19.3 x 15.8cm. Painted signature and date (LR): L.M. Wiles - / 1876. Painted title (plaque on frame). Handwritten (panel verso): View of Panama, C. America / L.M. Wiles / (LL) N.Y. 1876.
    View of dwelling along the water's edge surrounded by tropical vegetation; figure in small boat on the beach below at twilight.
  - [View in the Sierra Nevada Mountains, California], 1865; Wynat, Alexander Helvig; BANC PIC 1979.015--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 39 x 58.6 cm. Handwritten signature and date (LR): A. H. Wyant 1865.
    View of a broad, green meadow with a small encampment and horses in the middleground and a single Indian figure in the foreground.
    Oil paintings; Mountains -- Pictorial works; Landscapes (Representations) -- Sierra Nevada (Calif. and Nev.)
  - [The Mission of San Jose, California], [ca. 1826-1827]; Smyth, William; BANC PIC 1979.016--D (sheet 2-3); 1 drawing on paper (on 2 contiguous sketch book pages): pencil; full sheet 26.3 x 74.3 cm. Handwritten title (UL right hand sheet): The Mission of S. Jose. California -.
    William Smyth (watercolorist and topographical artist) served as official artist of Captain Frederick W. Beechey's expedition to the Pacific and Bering Strait on the ship H.M.S. Blossom under the command of Captain Beechey in 1825-1828. The expedition wintered in San Francisco and Monterey Bays in 1826 and 1827. While in California, Smyth made drawings and watercolors of the flora and fauna, among other subjects.
    Broad view of mission and outbuildings with two Indians in the foreground, a horse and rider to the right and native American dwellings (huts) to the left.
    Spanish mission buildings -- California -- Pictorial works; Drawings; Pencil works
  - Santa Anna [Church?] Panama, 1860; Nahl, Hugo Wilhelm Arthur; BANC PIC 1979.017--FR; 1 painting: oil; 20.5 x 28 cm. Painted signature and date (LL): A.N. 1860. Painted title (LR): Santa Anna Panama.
    Western façade of mission church looking towards east end of building; figures gathered around entrance and walking in street.
  - Hills near Salinas [Calif.], [19--?]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1979.018--D; 1 painting paper mounted on board: watercolor; 37.9 x 55.6 cm. Handwritten title (verso): Hills near Salinas. Manufacturer's stamp (verso): Whatman (extra hard sized drawing paper on board).
    View looking across open field with rolling hills in distance, possibily showing Gavilan Peak?